https://www.wyscouts.org.uk/terms/

Writing from home
‘More in Common’
Updates
WYSMail
WYSYouthable
What’s New !
Water Activity Equipment Hire
Access to, and use of, the West Yorkshire Scouts website is subject to the following Terms and Conditions of use.
West Yorkshire Scouts may change this policy from time to time by updating this page. You should check this page from time to time to ensure that you are happy with any changes. This policy is effective from 1st January 2015.
Copyright
West Yorkshire Scouts own the copyright and all associated intellectual property rights in the written contents, structure and layout of this Website.
Prior permission, in writing, is required from West Yorkshire Scouts for users or any third party to
Copy, or do any other act, in relation to these pages
Show the contents of this Website in a frame surrounded by other material in respect of which we have no involvement
Include any of the pages of this Website in any commercial document (whether electronic or otherwise) or as part of any material sold or made available for profit in any other way
Store or reproduce any part of this Website on another website
Communicate, reproduce or otherwise distribute to the public (whether in electronic form or otherwise) any part of this Website for any commercial purpose
Users of this website are permitted to
Display the contents of this website on their computer screen
Download to a hard drive or print any of these pages (without any changes being made to thereto) for personal (non-commercial) use only
Provide a link to this Website from other websites copy parts of this Website to third parties for their own private (non-commercial) use, subject to West Yorkshire Scouts being acknowledged as the source of any such parts and any such third parties being informed that these Terms and Conditions apply to their use and must be strictly adhered to
Important things you need to know !
The material on this website
Is provided for general information and interest only, and whilst all reasonable steps are taken to keep the material up to date, complete and accurate, we accept no responsibility for any damage or loss arising from reliance thereon
May include links to third party web sites. However, no responsibility is accepted or endorsement intended regarding the contents of, or material contained on, any such third party site
Whilst we take all reasonable steps to try to avoid viruses being present on this website, no responsibility is accepted for any viruses which may affect any material which users download.
About your Privacy
Data Protection
The following is a broad description of the way West Yorkshire Scouts/data controller processes personal information. To understand how your own personal information is processed you may need to refer to any personal communications you have received, check any privacy notices West Yorkshire Scouts has provided or contact us to ask about your personal circumstances.
Reasons/purposes for processing information
We process personal information to enable us to; provide a voluntary service for the benefit of the public in a particular geographical area as specified in our constitution; administer membership records; to fund raise and promote the interests of the charity; manage our employees and volunteers; maintain our own accounts and records; manage our centres (Bradley Wood and Green Withens); and organise events on behalf of the charity.
Type/classes of information processed
We process information relevant to the above reasons/purposes. This may include:
personal details
family details
lifestyle and social circumstances
membership details
goods and services
financial details
education and employment details
We also process sensitive classes of information that may include:
physical or mental health details
racial or ethnic origin
religious or other beliefs of a similar nature
Who the information is processed about
We process personal information about:
members
staff, volunteers
trustees
complainants, supporters
enquirers
advisers and representatives of other organisations
customers of our Bradley Wood and Green Withens Centres
Who the information may be shared with
We sometimes need to share the personal information we process with the individual themself and also with other organisations. Where this is necessary we are required to comply with all aspects of the Data Protection Act (DPA) 2017, implementing the EU General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR). What follows is a description of the types of organisations we may need to share some of the personal information we process with for one or more reasons.
Where necessary or required we share information with:
members
family, associates or representatives of the person whose personal data we are processing
employees
current, past and prospective employers
healthcare, social and welfare organisations
educators and examining bodies
financial organisations
employment and recruitment agencies
survey or research organisations
business associates and professional advisers
providers of goods and services
local and central government
other voluntary and charitable organisations
CCTV for crime prevention
CCTV is used for maintaining the security of property and premises and for preventing and investigating crime. It may also be used to monitor staff when carrying out work duties. For these reasons the information processed may include visual images, personal appearance and behaviours. This information may be about staff, customers and clients, offenders and suspected offenders, members of the public and those inside, entering or in the immediate vicinity of the area under surveillance. Where necessary or required this information is shared with the data subjects themselves, employees and agents, services providers, police forces, security organisations and persons making an enquiry.
Data Subject Access Request
Should you wish to enquire whether or not we process information about you or make a request for a copy of any personal information which West Yorkshire County Council holds about you, you should write to the Data Protection Officer by email to dpo@wyscouts.org.uk, outlining the personal data you are seeking to obtain. We will acknowledge your request and we will respond to you within 30 days of receiving it. We may need to verify your identity and ask you to clarify the data you are seeking to obtain (the 30 days will start from when your identity has been verified and the data you wish to obtain clarified).
Right to erasure (Right to be forgotten)
Should you wish us to erase any personal information that West Yorkshire Scouts holds about you, then you should write to the Data Protection Officer by email to dpo@wyscouts.org.uk. We will acknowledge your request by email, confirm whether we are able to erase the information requested (including confirming whether we hold it) and confirm to you once erased. We may need to verify your identity and ask you to clarify the data you are seeking to erase. We will consider each request on a case-by-case basis and whilst we will not seek to refuse your request unreasonably, we do have a number of statutory obligations that we must comply with. These include our vetting and safeguarding procedures, which may prevent us from being able to fully erase your personal data.
Correcting inaccurate personal data
Should you believe that the personal data we hold about you may be inaccurate, you can write to the Data Protection Officer by email to dpo@wyscouts.org.uk outlining the inaccuracy. We will acknowledge your email, seek to address the inaccuracy and confirm back to you once corrected.
Photography Policy
During West Yorkshire Scout events and activities, members of our media team, other members of the Scout Association and members of the public may be taking still and moving pictures. Pictures used by West Yorkshire Scout County outside of the event/activity will only be used in accordance with Scout Association guidelines. Pictures taken by our media team may be used during and after the event/activity in West Yorkshire Scouts or the Scout Association publications, and in local newspapers, on websites or in other media channels. Local newspapers and TV stations may also attend events/activities to provide external media coverage and members of the press will be accompanied at all times by a member of the event or activity staff/leader team. We will seek your specific permission if we wish to use your/your child’s picture in any promotional or advertising material.
Anyone attending any West Yorkshire Scouts County event or activity, or giving permission for their child/ward to attend an event or activity should note that attendance at the event or activity signifies their consent for pictures of themselves/their child to be used in line with the above policy. If you have specific concerns in this regard, please contact the specific event/activity manager.
Website Information : How we use cookies
A cookie is a small file which asks permission to be placed on your computer’s hard drive. Once you agree, the file is added and the cookie  helps analyse web traffic or lets you know when you visit a particular site. Cookies allow web applications to respond to you as an individual. The web application can tailor its operations to your needs, likes and dislikes by gathering and remembering information about your preferences.
We use traffic log cookies to identify which pages are being used. This helps us analyse data about web page traffic and improve our website in order to tailor it to customer needs. We only use this information for statistical analysis purposes and then the data is removed from the system.
Overall, cookies help us provide you with a better website, by enabling us to monitor which pages you find useful and which you do not. A cookie in no way gives us access to your computer or any information about you, other than the data you choose to share with us.
You can choose to accept or decline cookies. Most web browsers automatically accept cookies, but you can usually modify your browser setting to decline cookies if you prefer. This may prevent you from taking full advantage of the website.
YouTube cookies
We embed videos from our official YouTube channel using YouTube’s privacy-enhanced mode. This mode may set cookies on your computer once you click on the YouTube video player, but YouTube will not store personally-identifiable cookie information for playbacks of embedded videos using the privacy-enhanced mode. To find out more please visit YouTube’s embedding videos information page.
Twitter cookies
We embed tweets from our official Twitter channels using “Twitter for websites”. When you view Twitter content or Twitter products integrated into our websites using Twitter for Websites, Twitter may receive information including the web page you visited, your IP address, browser type, operating system, and cookie information. To find out more information please visit: https://dev.twitter.com/web/overview/privacy
Facebook Cookies
We embed content from our official facebook accounts using “Facebook Technologies”.  When you view facebook content or facebook products integration into our websites using “facebook technologies”, Facebook uses cookies and receives information when you visit those sites and apps, including device information and information about your activity, without any further action from you. This occurs whether or not you have a Facebook account or are logged in. To find out more information please visit : https://www.facebook.com/policies/cookies/
Google Analytics Cookies
Visitors to this website who have javascript enabled are tracked using Google Analytics. Google Analytics collects the following types of information from users:
·         Type of user agent (web browser) used, software manufacture and version number.
·         Type of operating system
·         Screen colors (color processing ability of the users screen)
·         Javascript support
·         Flash version
·         Screen resolution
·         Network location and IP address
·         Can include country, city, state, region, county, or any other geographic data.
·         Hostname
·         Bandwidth (internet connection speed)
·         Time of visit
·         Pages visited
·         Time spent on each page of the website
·         Referring site statistics
·         The website (URI) the user came through in order to arrive at this website (example: clicking on a hyperlink from Yahoo.com that took the user to this website)
·         Search engine query used (example: typing in a phrase into a search engine like Google, and clicking on a link from that search engine)
This data is only used to optimize our website for our visitors.
This data DOES NOT include any personalized identification information such as:
·         Names
·         Phone numbers
·         Email addresses
·         Mailing addresses
·         Bank account numbers
·         Credit card information
Click here for an overview of privacy at Google. To opt out of being tracked by Google Analytics across all websites visit http://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout.
Links to other websites
Our website may contain links to other websites of interest. However, once you have used these links to leave our site, you should note that we do not have any control over that other website. Therefore, we cannot be responsible for the protection and privacy of any information which you provide whilst visiting such sites and such sites are not governed by this privacy statement. You should exercise caution and look at the privacy statement applicable to the website in question.
WYSMAIL
West Yorkshire Scouts Mailing and Information list (WYSMAIL) is managed through a mailing list provider, in order to subscribe to the mailing list we use a double opt in option, meaning that users need to subscribe themselves and then follow an email link to confirm subscription.  Subscribers can unsubscribe at any point following the link at the bottom of the email.  Visit our mailing list providors website to view their privacy policy
Event Bookings
For our event bookings we use a third party provider – Bookwhen , visit their website to view their privacy policy.
Archives and Heritage
National Heritage Centre
Contact Members of the County
Our Years in Review
Safeguarding Policy
Privacy Policy
Our Local DistrictsAire Valley
Bradford North
National Scouts
Latest TweetsWestYorkshire ScoutsFollow8 Nov@HelenSykes @wyscouts @BearGrylls ....and what a lovely family picture!8 NovVery strange not being out on remembrance day parades, we still paid our respects @wyscouts @TimothyKidd @BearGrylls Load More...
About Us
Your Local Districts
Aire Valley
Bradford North
Bradford South
Brighouse
Halifax
Heavy Woollen
‘More in Common’
Updates
WYSMail
WYSYouthable
What’s New !
By continuing to use the site, you agree to the use of cookies.
More InformationAccept
